

404 NE Richardson Pl Lee's Summit, MO 64086 (816) 853-8049

> alan@icant.dance Find me on Github Find me on LinkedIn

I specialize in building large-scale applications in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, with a fair amount of PHP thrown into the mix to keep things interesting. I have a love for testing; every project I touch has automated tests such as Jasmine, Mocha, and Ava unit tests, as well as end-to-end tests with Nightwatch or Codeception with Selenium.

In my spare time when I am not learning new coding concepts or working on side projects, you can find me playing Magic: the Gathering with my friends or spending time binging on Netflix under a cat pile with my girlfriend.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
 - Vue
 - React
 - Phaser
 - D3
 - Jasmine/Karma
 - Mocha/Chai/Sinon
 - Ava
 - Nightwatch
- HTML5
- SASS/LESS/CSS3
 - Bootstrap

- Passion for Agile/Scrum
- Section 508 compliance
- PHP
 - Laravel
- Codeception/Selenium
- MySQL
- Git
- Vagrant
- Ansible
- Gulp/Webpack/Browserify

EXPERIENCE

Fire Engine Red, Software Developer, Team Lead Remote / Dec 2014 – Current

Coding daily in a combination of Vue and jQuery on top of Laravel daily, and have worked extensively on JavaScript unit tests in Jasmine and end-to-end Codeception tests. Our software has to be scalable for clients with hundreds of thousands of records and is used daily by college admissions offices across the country.

Mindgrub Technologies, Software Engineer Baltimore, MD / July 2014 – Dec 2014

JavaScript (Phaser) games and Angular were the primary focus, along with building WordPress sites for a variety of clients. Integrated headless backend APIs into front-end frameworks for consumption and display.

Freelance Web Development, Web Developer Remote / February 2010 – Current

Maintained and developed various WordPress based websites and plugins. Had some minor exposure to bug fixes in CakePHP and did some branding work. Worked with Vue on various side projects.

Yoko Consulting, Web Developer

Remote / March 2013 – July 2013

Worked primarily with multiple, socially-focused user sites built on the WordPress platform with plugin and API integration ranging from Authorize.net to bbPress and BuddyPress. Also maintained various backup systems and hosting across a distributed network on a LAMP platform.

Voltage Creative, Junior/Senior Web Developer Kansas City, MO / Jan 2012 – March 2013

Created and maintained a wide variety of Websites built upon the WordPress platform, and also maintained several LAMP and MAMP stacks to run these sites. The sites were all designed by others within our offices, but a lot of the back-end PHP and front-end JavaScript code had my hands dirty.

More work history available upon request.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Bachelor of Arts

William Jewell College, Liberty, MO - Completed May 2007 (3.92 GPA)

Graduated in the top 10% of my class from William Jewell College and received the Computer Science Faculty Award for the outstanding senior in Computer Science and Information Systems.

Heart of America Regional Computer Forensics Laboratory, Intern Kansas City, MO June 2006 – Aug 2006

Upgraded, maintained and implemented various PHP based software solutions for the FBI. Secret level government clearance was required, which I obtained after a rigorous background check.